Alright, let's start that clock here.
Alright, you have three hours.
Clock, there we go. Um, and it's
my opportunity to, uh, today to apply for a role at,
uh, all hands.
And we're gonna I'm going to do that with, that coding exercise.
Umm, that has been assigned.
Let me just let everybody know who I am here.
This is, uh, you probably don't need a picture because you see me right
now, but just so you remember who I am.
Um, I'm John Shackleford, currently working,
um, independently with, um,
Palomar Digital. Um. Um, my own little startup,
uh, with a former colleague of mine. And,
um, today we're going to be doing tic-tac-toe.
Alright. So, um,
I think what I want to do,
I'm going to divide my three hours into six,
thirty minute chunks. And the very first one,
on is going to be mostly about, you know,
getting things set up and getting the foundations laid for real productivity.
And then, the last thirty minutes is going to be for kind of final
polish and make sure we get to the end of something that's worth showing.
Um, and, uh,
so that gives me, you know, really four thirty minute chunks to- it,
um, great features in. So I want to talk a little bit about my
approach to the project. Um, but,
while I do that, and while I can prepare some other notes about the
project, I want an agent running in the background to make the best use
of time. So, I'm going to start by getting,
um, the first bit going, and then we'll come back and look at,
Umm, my approach to the project and,
and that sort of thing. Okay. So first what I'm going to do is,
um, do a little voice recording,
and, and that'll just make it easier for me to prompt,
um, AI for the first bit.
So I'm using a little utility that's part of the Limsie Suite I've been
working on, and,
we just want the speech command,
or the recording command,
and, uh, just make sure I remember how to do it.
Oh, let's see. Are we using the wrong?
Alright, let's see if that works.
Alright, so, Umm,
dash F, and dash meter?
Okay. ,ish F,
and then we'll put it on the desktop. And this will be my
umm,
Oh, it's okay. Alright.
All right. Umm,
so we're going to be building a tic-tac-toe game,
and the first thing that we want to do is get the model classes
right. And umm,
I want to keep the model separate from other functions,
umm, because this could get incorporated,
umm, into lots of different.
You know, possible projects. So,
no display logic, just the model.
And umm, we want to use, uhh, vtest,
and umm, we want to use umm,
the latest, umm, LTS version of node.
And umm, I'm going to be using uhh,
uhh, a template project to- use MPM,
or PMPM, umm,
to set up, umm, monorepo,
because we're likely have a number of different components.
Let's talk about the model for the FixActo game.
So we're going to need umm,
something that represents the game board, and umm,
the game state, and umm, history of the turns that are taken uhh,
uhh, we're going to need a player, and we're going to need umm,
a way for different players to play,
human players, umm, different AI players,
and so on. So we want to make sure that umm,
that the model is flexible and allows for umm,
that, and that, that, uhh,
uhh, that the API easily accom- .
It's, umm, different turn takers. Umm,
I'm trying to think of there are any other things that we
need to think about. Umm, we'll have a couple of different AI's to start
with. We'll have a random turn taker that just takes the first available turn.
Or, you know, a random of, of the available turns.
Umm, and,
Umm, the other thing I think is kind of interesting is,
you know, how do you compute the best move in tic-tac-toe?
You know, if it were a more complicated game,
you would use like a red black tree or something like that to kind
of like, you know, find the best move for something like tic-tac-toe.
There's really only eight ways to win.
So, um, it would be not,
Nice if we could get, um,
some output analysis to
help us with, um, kind of that,
the action space versus the,
you know, the game environment and, um,
so, um,
knowing, you know, what the available,
turn options are, it would be important.
Um, I think I also want to have, like,
a grid system so that you could easily refer to turns with,
like, letters representing columns, numbers representing rows.
Um, what else do we want in there?
Um, I'm trying to
think of anything else we need to think about.
For tic-tac-toe. Oh,
yeah, I know. It would be kind of nice to have,
um,
a function in our game engine that would,
umm, that would- tell us sort of what the-
available,
you know, what-what the next best moves are for
each player, you know, in-in ranked order.
Um, and-and in other words, like, uh,
you know, here's a move that could win in one turn.
Here's a move that could end in two-win in two turns.
Here's a move that would-could win in- three turns,
um, so that you could, you know,
kind of rank them that way. Um, that might be,
uh, kind of duplicate from- what
you would do with a red black tree if we ever use such a
thing. Um, trying to think if there's any other core
ideas we need in the item.
I don't. I don't think so. Okay,
so this is going to go in the lib directory, um,
of our packages directory in our,
um, in our project.
Okay, I think that's enough. And now let's,
uh, go ahead and see
if we can- sorry for moving. and just a little picture around.
So, oh.
That's time. There it is.
There it is. Okay. So,
uh, let's go ahead and make a code directory for this.
Make sure. Code.
Actually, I want to do it like this.
Yes.
And, we're gonna open up cursor,
and we're gonna- and
I.
It's a goodness I'm showing up.
That's interesting.
Alright, let me just, whoa,
no, don't do that!
I'll just do it like this. I'm gonna create a little dog folder
here. There.
And, bring that in
there. Okay. And that's the original
set of instructions that we received.
So now I should be able to. Got it.
It'll be referenced by active type. Okay. So the next thing I want to
do is,
umm,
let's have the agent think about that for a minute.
Now, it will do some summarizing.
But while it's doing that, what I want to do is find a design
document that I have a specific format I like to use for design documents.
So, I'm going to try.
I'm going to find a good example.
And, let's see,
I think, in the Allen project I have.
A bunch of,
um.
And, I think this one for,
I think it was something that would have been a different branch.
Yeah, yeah. This,
this branch is a little better.
There we go.
Huh. Why is it not letting me click?
Alright. Yeah,
I think like this one,
a conversation history. I thought I had an M2 in here that was good.
Oh, I'll bet that's in a different branch. M2 branch.
Okay. I mean, these are all pretty much the same,
but umm, this one came out pretty well.
Umm. Umm. Umm.
Umm. Start on the A design.
Actually, let's get that from the template.
But. That I'm gonna use. Think if I go back to
GitHub. Umm,
aaand, kind of my repositories.
PMPM template. This is just a nice template that already
has my GitHub workflow. And,
you know, tools I like to use. You Alrighty to go.
So, I can get started easier with that.
I wasn't sure if doing that would be cheating. Umm,
to use that template. But I did ask Ash.
I think I have a little picture. You should've said.
Basically, she said. It's okay.
So, thank you, Ash. Umm.
Alright. So,
there is our repo structure. sure
Alright. So now,
let me give it that design dock.
Okay. Here
is the um, design dock format.
I like it. I like to
use. Uhm,
please stop at the end
of section 2,
because we will do-
discuss. And then,
um, where-where is that document gonna go?
Let's put it in tic-tac-toe.
Let's call-let's call tic-tac-toe T3. Okay.
Um, and we're gonna put that in the-and we'll
just say.
Alright. And that'll keep it busy for a bit.
Because there's quite a bit to that. That, um, design document.
And now I think we can talk about,
kind of my whole approach to this problem.
And, um, so I'm gonna do another recording. To capture that.
And, um, I don't know. Just,
bring up a record again.
Let me see.
Okay. So now we're talking about the project as a whole.
So, um. I'm,
One of the things that, umm,
you'll notice in the technical assessment is that,
you know, the time limit is really critical. And for me,
that will be the biggest challenge. It's sort of balancing. How do I slow
down and show, like, that I know,
engineering disciplines? Um, and,
you know, actually I'm fast enough to be productive.
You know, I think the biggest thing is, like, avoiding tarpets because,
um, it doesn't take much to sink three hours if you get stuck on
something. So, having this, you know,
every 30 minutes stop is gonna help me.
In fact, how am I doing on time? I'm accidentally paused it.
Unpause. Um, so,
how am I doing? So,
I guess I've got just a few minutes left.
Um, now, um,
okay, let's talk about, ah, anyway.
Uh, it says here you could do a
basic, simple front end. You could do a CLI.
You could do a back end.
Umm, API. You could do a containerized deployment.
You could deploy it, and so on. Okay, so, thank for me.
The main thing is, you have to have something,
right? It has to be a playable tic-tac-toe game. And so,
I think our goal is to be able to reduce risk in this project
by get to something playable as fast as possible.
And then make it better or do con- and interesting projects,
um, you know, after that basic part was done.
So, what would be like the most basic implementation of tic-tac-toe?
Well, um, I was recently playing tic-tac-toe with my kids in the car on
a long trip. Uh, I was trying to keep them busy,
and so we decided that we would try like like mental tic-tac-toe,
you know, where you didn't actually get,
See the board, you just said, you know, A1,
you know, B2, and so on.
And, um, that was a lot of fun for them, for the younger ones.
And, um, that would be simple.
We wouldn't have to think about any kind of layout, or presentation,
or, you know. As long as the game engine works,
and you can, you know,
give your moves, and simple, you know,
roll. role. We'll call them type, or column row type format,
then you're fine. Um, so I think that's the first implementation.
And, of course, the whole library is,
is then there. And then we could start doing other things.
We could do a React app, um,
or more sophisticated CLI version,
or something like that. I mean, things I would really love to do are,
like, the- voice, um,
voice-activated. That could be done either from the command line,
or it could be done in the browser using the kind of voice libraries
that are built into browsers nowadays. Um.
I mean, what I would love to do, actually, is have it on Apple
TV, and, um, like,
have your phone be the microphone,
you know, and so you could actually- Actually,
Play it talking to your phone, and then have it show up on Apple
TV. There's no way I'm doing that in three hours, so.
As much as I'd like to do that, that's off the table.
Uh, another thing that would be really cool,
be to do, like, a touch screen, Raspberry Pi,
you know, device. And I think I've got a touch screen that
I could use, and I could steal John Andrew's- Andrew. Just Raspberry Pi,
that would be fun. But that also is not gonna fit
in three hours, probably. So, um,
they're just limits to what we're gonna be able to do with the time
we've got. I think the main thing is,
um, if we do go down the React kind of road is like
there's all kinds of carpets you could fall into there. Um,
so let's, you know, be very careful about that.
Yeah. But we should be able to get the first thing up and going
in the first iteration or two. Okay.
So that's kind of how I'm thinking about this.
Um, I understand,
my understanding, let's talk about my understanding of what they want.
Um, yeah,
I want something playable. They want to see my process in the way I'm
thinking. Okay, I'm doing that right now, so, um,
hopefully they can read a transcript or summarize a transcript.
That's even better because this is being awfully long through your hours.
Um, what else?
Um, rules.
I talked about the clarification I got from Ash.
Any other sort of assumptions I'm making about rules that I should communicate?
Give me a kick. I think, uh,
an important one is I- there's nothing in the rules that says I can't
borrow code from other projects that I have worked on previously.
And, um, so I'll do that. Um,
my son and I have been writing little games all
summer, so there should be stuff to draw on.
Umm, any other rule assumptions I should communicate.
I don't think so. I think we're good. I think balancing the time
versus, like,
showing. I mean, one of the things they talk about here is using an
AI credically. So don't just,
like, accept the output. Obviously,
you know. It's garbage in,
garbage out with the AI tools anyway, so, um,
hopefully I can demonstrate that just as part of my natural workflow,
but I do need to be cognizant of that.
Okay, I think I've done all the thinking I need to do about how
I'm gonna approach the problem. Maybe we should be more specific about milestones.
stones. So milestone one is all about kind of getting the lip going,
getting our first, you know,
push in into GitHub, getting our workflows running,
you know, basic infrastructure. Interation two,
like dead simple command line version,
or doesn't even have to have a command line interface if I can kick
it off. But it has to be playable tic-tac-toe.
I think we're gonna do that by just no display.
Mental tic-tac-toe. Umm. And against a random player,
right? Um, that's milestone, uh,
two. And then, milestone three,
and four, um, and five,
couldn't be, uh, about, like, more sophisticated CLI,
or react, or, and I think the way that I'm gonna approach that is,
I'm gonna build design documents for everything.
Um, and then,
I'm going- Thank much for joining me. To, um,
run a bunch of those through,
um, a cursor agent in parallel,
and, you know,
we'll take what we get, you know, we'll take the good stuff from the
output we get, and we'll discard the rest,
and we'll just, you know,
try to end with something good by, uh, being selective about,
um. . . what we pull in and what we think we can finish
and polish. Um, but we won't be, like,
I think taking some risks is okay,
we just gotta be very careful about time-boxing.
Okay, I've talked enough about all this,
and I hope I'm still recording.
Looks like it. Alright,
so now, I should have an approach.
How much. Uh,
transcript here.
Not nearly as many words as you would think it would be.
Uhm, for as much time as it took. So,
let's uh, turn.
Now, let's look at, um, what happened with our other design document here.
Alright. So we-
We've got the problem statement, post solution,
demo implementation standards.
Uhh, uhh, okay,
there's stuff about demos that I think can be removed.
Good assumptions. I'm sure I'm on this. Or a few board
moving illnesses. Okay,
here's our classes. Game
board, game state player. Game engine move analyzer.
Umm. Not sure
if I see anything that represents the actions. 4 4 5 Space.
And, Oh, you know, I never told it that we were doing TypeScript.
That was not good. Sorry.
It's an easy fix later. Okay,
so let's interact here. How
will we get- at the action space from
the current state?
Okay, great.
I'm gonna make some improvements. I'm gonna move this around.
I'm sorry that I keep moving this little bubble around. I have to be
able to see what's going on here. Umm,
uhh, so,
I'm not seeing what you actually changed here.
Did you?
Okay. Okay,
good. Alright, so now,
What's,
actions from the template are left.
left.
1, 2, 3 and 4. I'm a little bit more.
Okay, while it's doing that, let's clone our template repo and
get going with that bit.
Alright, so where is that template repo?
Oh, it's right here. I must have pulled
it up a moment ago, okay. So,
I guess what I could do is just,
let's say I used this template, create a new repository.
And we're gonna call this open plugins T.
Two. Two. Two. Three. Umm,
and we're gonna make it private. And
we're gonna just create it. And we'll just say that this is our take
assessment project. Alright,
there we go. Getting worried about the time.
fine. Oh, we're almost at the end of the first section.
Okay. So here's our all hands T3
project. And I'm gonna get cloned that.
Okay. And now,
I'm gonna copy.
This are the tic-tac-toe docs
directory into the new repo.
Cause that's where we're gonna work from now on. Oh,
it was T3.0.
All of our docs there. Alright, great. All
right, now, of course, it's still working on the design doc,
so I'm gonna have to do that again, actually. Umm.
But, that's okay. It doesn't stop us from making sure that
the tests run. Oh,
we have to install everything,
right? Oh,
okay. Let's look at the template. What am I doing wrong here?
Pnpm, let's don't, uhm.
Okay. And,
set up the GitHub Hux.
Okay, great. And then let's run.
And the build.
And then let's just do,
Let's just go straight to the test.
Pnpm test.
Great, test ran. And so.
Oh. Stavis.
Uhm. Let's actually.
Finally.
And we're just gonna say.
Look at the. Docks.
We want to look at the read me.
Read me and. time. We want to look at the.
This is hard on the eyes. Ahhh. Okay.
And we want to look also at our approach stock.
Approach stock. And maybe we
should also include the assignment.
Umm. Mm. Just that drop in
there.
Is that- is that seeing it? I'm not sure it's seeing it.
Is it in the dark folder? Oh.
No.
Let's also include that.
And then say, let's update the readme.
Keeping. Keeping. Dev.
Workflow. But.
Adding. Initial.
Okay, great. We're gonna get out.
Yeah. Alright.
How are we doing? It's working on our design.
It's good. Now,
wait a minute. I can see.
There's a bunch of changes up here. Yeah.
It did successfully get rid of the demo stuff we didn't want.
But I'm not seeing, did it actually give us all the testing content
that we want?
Can you imagine an actual space?
I was having it, um,
I have trouble with
the edit tools today. For some reason,
it's just really struggling with the edit tools today. Yeah,
so a lot of this content is missing. So,
Let's see, can we just apply it?
No. Copy it.
Okay, so I'm just gonna copy it.
Oh, good, and there's the section 4 content too.
Great.
And, looks like it did have some kind of edit problem.
So what I'm gonna do is just let it know that there's an
edit problem.
Looks like,
was a problem applying edits in
the middle of the dark between,
I'll just say here. So it has line references.
So if we do it like this, it'll get the line references,
it'll know where to look. Okay.
And umm, let's see how our bell is done over
here. Let's see. Oh, we were working on the read me.
Let's go back to the, Where is the read me?
It's in a different instance of cursor which,
Which is where. No.
Here's our read me. Here's our new read me content.
Let's fix all the lint errors. Pretty particular.
But yeah, it doesn't care, but I care.
Okay. It's how we're good.
So let's get this bit
out of the read me. See you.
And there's no new content because we started from a clone.
Okay. Get.
And what are we saying? We're saying we updated the reading.
That's it. Read me. First.
So Husky's working. Now we're pushing.
And we'll see if our GitHub project works.
Okay. Umm.
on Alright, let's see how our little
dock is coming here. It looks like they deleted those lines.
Good. What's down here? These are just basic little lint
errors. We can give it off.
And, It did not follow the,
It's interesting that it, um,
If followed the template well enough to know that it's supposed to identify implementation
and test steps, but it's also supposed to include test
files. miles.
And, um, so I'm gonna tell it to do that.
Actually, this might be a good time to switch over to our new project.
So, a moment ago I did a little copy operation
here. Where was that? So
let's just do that. Let's be specific,
because we've only changed one file.
That's gonna go in the dock. Okay.
And now from now on, we're not gonna be in this project.
We're gonna be in this one, right? Are we?
Yes. Okay.
Now, this is in my way,
sorry. Um, okay.
Let's,
Let's have it fix this document. Thank you very much for your
And that should be in, uhm,
ehm. I could just lib, source,
uhm,
test. Uhm,
be sure our tests are using v-test.
Next.
And, uhm,
our checklist section.
Every sub section should have
both code implementations.
Let's let it fix that dock. And let's
see how our build did. So here's our all
hands T3 project. Let's go to GitHub actions.
And, good.
Sweet.
Test results. Yes,
good. Co-coverage reports.
words.
Okay, great. That's what we want to see.
So, what's next?
Sorry, build is good. We just,
we need this design dark to wrap up.
Then we'll give that to an agent, and then we'll start working- right on
the design docks for the other pieces.
So, how are we doing on time here? Well, we,
we finished our first iteration.
We're halfway through the second one. Um,
I feel like we're running behind by maybe 15,
20 minutes of where I want it to be, but I think we'll,
we'll be, we'll be alright.
Let's see how these dark edits are going.
Good, good. This is what I want to see. Full file paths.
Um, you can save a ton of problems when you're,
you know, generating code, um,
in a batch by being very specific about,
the, uh, the files, where they are.
Umm, cause, ha. Stupid,
it's really stupid things that can get the agent confused and waste a lot
of cycles, like, it'll get there eventually,
but it might take way more turns than necessary.
Some of these don't have changes yet.
Oh, okay. There's, there's, they're kind of,
it's gonna workin' through. I'm not through. Slowly workin' through the doc.
Getting those files. And so it hasn't gotten to the checklist section,
which is what I'm really concerned about. That's super important to
have, woah, a really strong checklist section.
That's where the magic happens.
Umm, sometimes when it's doing test strategy stuff,
it just says, like, really general stuff it already knows.
That's not very helpful. It's much better if it's actually,
it's more specific.
Umm. You
This is taking a long time. . . Well,
I gotta know what I've expected.
Okay. So there's enough here that I can open
a new tab. And say,
what to create a new dot.
. .
It looks like this thing is ready to go. I'm seeing.
Teen. Test.
That's good.
Oftentimes the last parts of a checklist,
it's funny. It's like a human in the sense that,
you know, we understand the stuff that's
near to it. And the stuff that's a little further out is kind of
hand wavy. And, um, almost always when writing these documents,
the AI will, like,
append to the end, like, considerations about performance or security,
or, you know, boilerplate stuff it's seen in other design docs.
But it's just boilerplate. Like, there's no actual meaningful content besides the boiler,
um, plate stuff. And that's kind of what's happening here.
. Here is, you know, says we should have API documentation.
Okay. Well, we're actually building that right now. So,
I'm not gonna bother with this. All this,
kind of, final validation stuff.
It's very hand wavy. And I'm just gonna delete it all.
That, that is a pretty typical pattern with these.
But this stuff is good.
Integration testing, testing infrastructure.
This stuff, we're not gonna need it. We're not gonna need this.
That's done. Integration
test directory. Sure.
Let's do integration testing.
Okay. That seems reasonable.
It seems reasonable.
And if there are big problems with the design,
it will come out. Pretty quick.
Pretty quick. So at this point,
I think we are ready to have an agent's,
start building that out. So we are going
to go in the background mode. And we are going to tell it,
oops. Umm,
implement. Doc.
What did we call this? Just. Come on.
Pop, pop, pop, pop. Shh.
Umm, completing each sub
section of the check list
e4. See,
two. Next. Next.
In sharing. Test.
Pass. And.
Uhm. Mm. Mm.
You complete them.
Uhm, and then what do you need to do? You need to, uhm,
commit and push one.
It's green for
every subsection.
uhh, uhh, uhh,
uhh, uhh, uhh, and we need to push two.
Yeah.
This.
Is there anything else? I feel like I'm forgetting something that it always messes
up, but I'm not. It's not.
Oh, I know our agent is probably not set up.
So we need to go in here. It needs to know
about our repo.
Umm, umm. Mm-hmm.
Oh, I wonder if we actually got the,
No, I don't think so.
Yeah, I'm not seeing the cursor file that sh-has the agent set up.
up.
I live dangerously. I-I use the,
the beta versions of, umm,
cursor, so, like, new stuff comes out all the time.
Sometimes it's broken, and this might be one of those times.
Uh-huh. Let's see if this will do it.
Good. Saw that.
Oh, yeah, I gotta come in and push that.
Get add.cursor.
Uhh, let's see. Oh,
it's because it's at the wrong level,
probably. No, it isn't. Which,
where are we? Oh,
I'm at the wrong level.
There we go. Status.
I think we can, we can add our dock to.
That's going to be, super important, actually. Let's add the contract stock.
Actually, that's just out of mall. They're all good for now.
I mean, we're going to have to revise some of them still. Uhm,
okay.
Get them in. This is what's called darks.
It's Muslim darks.
Okay. Now.
Potentially outdated environment.
That's interesting.
Why does it think the environment is outdated?
Okay, things are okay. Oh,
that's interesting. What happened? Oh, oh,
oh, I'll be- That is because, umm,
the linter. Hehehe.
Okay. Commit.
And then we're going to of a
Alright. There we
go. Repository access required.
Set up. Continue. And.
And, What do you want to
do? Oh, it's all through, okay. Install another address.
You know what? The other thing I'm gonna set up is Google Quotuses.
Where do you want to come to assist today? Quotuses.
GitHub. Install.
Marketplace right here. And they're somewhere installed
for free. Ooh, I picked the wrong account prior.
It doesn't, man.
This is me, I think, right?
Select repositories. Sweet.
Sweet. Ah. Okay. Alright.
Where are we? So.
Are we pose? There is.
Okay, as I read me, I can't
be in the, template stuff. Okay. And,
I think we had a,
we already verified we have a clean bill. That hasn't changed.
And, pretty soon we're gonna be seeing some pull requests show up here.
Let's see how the umm, let's see how that our little agent is doing.
Ooh, background agent not found. That's not good.
What's that all about?
Oh, there it goes.
I just felt the start. All right. All right.
Okay. Sweet. It's working on that.
While it starts, I'm going to go turn on the air conditioner for a
minute. I hope it's not going to make too much noise for you,
for background, but, um. It's,
I'm afraid I'm going to need a little air for just a bit.
Okay. And then, we'll come back and more.
We're going to some design docks. Fox. Mm-mm.
Okay. Hopefully, that's not too noisy for you. Okay.
We're coming up on the end of the,
actually we've blown past the end of our first hour,
so we've got to get bookin'. I wanted to see a tic-tac-toe game by
now, and we're still doing, like, a lot of kind of setup activity.
I mean- . Fundamentally,
we're laying the groundwork for all that cool stuff that's gonna happen,
so. Umm,
I'm okay. I'm okay with it, but. Alright.
We can put all this aside, not right now.
And. Let's start working on some new design
docks. So,
we want one for this. 2,
3, see the line. I'm ready.
And we're gonna want one for,
umm, a react.
2, 3.
Fastify server, hmm. Fastify server.
Sir. Okay.
Time's running short, but let's- let's go ahead and-
Umm.
Okay, so to fastify,
dark, what's gonna be the best way to write that?
I think, the best way for
it to write that, I think that's gonna be- be best done by a
local agent, because I think what I'm gonna have it do,
is clone another repo and
look at it. And umm.
Yeah, that's what I'm gonna do. For that one.
I see a lot. Okay.
Let's see what kind of shape our contracts documents
in, because this is the basis for everything else we're gonna do.
And, Boy, building on this before we get the first review is
kind of risky. Because I think we're gonna find some API problems
in our first review of it.
Uhm,
but, I think that's
the right thing to do. Okay, so, do I wanna use,
what do I wanna use? Do I wanna use, like,
plain, Oh, cliff. For the CLI,
do I wanna build it on the Limsi CLI?
If I use the Limsi CLI, the advantage is that I have lots of
design docs and review guidelines and other stuff that can help me
do it right. Umm,
then you, on the other hand, you have to deal with the whole Limsi
ecosystem bit. Umm.
That might be pretty safe way to go,
except for the PMPM repository.
Let's just go plain Oak left to start.
Okay, so I'm going to do another little
recording here. Umm,
mz speed. Mm.
Text. And here,
we're going to, um, use meter.
Okay. Okay,
this is, these are notes for a design dock that we want.
For T-3, or tic-tac-toe,
um, CLI. And uh, CLI is going to provide a,
um, command-line client,
really simple one, for, um,
playing tic-tac-toe, um, but it's not gonna have any,
like, visual output. Uh,
I mean, it will, but it's just going to be,
pronting you, um, for your move,
and telling you what move it's gonna take.
Um, and we're gonna refer to the tic-tac-toe grid with lettered
columns, numbered rows, and,
um, we're going to use the existing model classes that are in
the lib directory. Um,
this CLI will be under,
um, Okay, okay. Umm, the package's CLI.
Um, it's gonna use Oakliff. Um,
we're gonna test it with the Oakliff testing tools.
And, um, I will,
um, append the,
um, the read me,
actually, I'll probably append the whole source code for the,
um, Oakliff testing tools to make sure that we use those properly.
Um, what else? Do we need to know about the CLI?
So, um, the command is gonna be,
Let's just make the command T3.
Um, and,
Let's,
You Let's make a command called,
So the topic will be called T3,
and the command will be called new.
And it's gonna command, Create a new game. And,
And then, um, the,
Um, It'll prompt for,
First it'll take a kind of a random coin flip to see who plays
first. S S First, the AI, or the human.
And, um, the,
um,
When it's the human string to play, um,
it'll just prompt using enquirer or something like that,
uh, to prompt you for your move,
which you'll give, like, A1 or B2 or something like that.
And then, um, the,
the AI will turn. We'll take its turn.
And then what will be displayed is a list of,
um, each of the turns. Um,
you know, Player 1, and then what they turned,
Player 2, what they moved,
and so on. Um, and then it'll announce the winner at the,
end of the game. Um, and that's all
we'll do to start with. Um, let's,
let's, that'll be Milestone 1. Milestone 2,
um, will introduce the concept of a match.
So there we need to add the concept of match to the lib directory.
And a match is, um,
the number of games. And,
um, so you can have a 5-game match,
for example. Or, you know, play 2 out of 3 for a 3-game match,
or 3 out of 5 for a 5-game match,
or so on. You, you specify the number of games in the
match. And then,
um, it'll go ahead and play a match
with. And, you know,
each turn, each turn, there'll be a,
um, a coin flip, um,
for who gets to start the first game. The second match,
um, or the second game in the match will be started by whoever didn't
get to play first, the first time. And it'll just alternate from there.
Umm. So,
yeah, the checklist in the design document should be organized into those two milestones,
umm, for the command line.
Alright, that's it.
Okay, so where is our,
where's our notes? There's our transcript.
And so we need to write a new design dark.
Mark.
And then, let's go get the Oak Lift test.
Oak Lift! Uh-uh,
uh-uh, uh-uh, uh-uh, uh-uh. We don't want- we want Oak Lift.
If we want get-up, it's not what we want.
Get-up. Oak Lift.
Core. No. Test.
And we're just gonna come in here to the source directory,
and there's index, and there's a raw.
Okay. So we got a new design document coming.
How is our agent doing? Is
he stuck? Just working on
the tests for the player.
Let's see if we've got any commits in that poll request yet.
He hasn't pushed anything.
I'm surprised. Why don't we have any pushes?
Can I ask him?
Sometimes what happens is that we don't actually-
yeah, it actually could be on a branch.
Let's look. Nope. Mm hmm.
That's highly unusual that it wouldn't,
usually it's pretty good about,
um, committing at each of those subsection boundaries.
So I'm kind of surprised, but especially if we've already got 120 turns already.
Um.
Alright, how are we doing here? Alright, it doesn't really matter.
Just thinking about it. That's pretty Now, gonna a, so is
Yeah, this is good. It's good.
Good.
We're gonna get some push this pretty soon here,
and then we can start reviewing it.
Yeah, it's funny. I have not seen it struggle with the edit tool,
like we are struggling today. So when you,
um, put auto here, instead of picking a particular model,
it's gonna use what ever model is,
kind of has the lowest load on it,
you know? Umm, and,
it's gonna do it free. That's a nice reason to choose that,
and it's gonna be fast. Umm,
but you don't always get the best model when you're doing that.
So sometimes it's necessary to start off.
Over with a better model. Happily,
if we stop it and restart it,
we'll get, you know, all the same context.
Oh, good. Here we go.
There's our command structure.
Okay, control our clients.
Okay, it didn't, it didn't really- Listen to the instructions that
we gave it.
It's, um.
And sometimes, you know, if it gets going, it just can't help itself,
you know what I mean? I just, like, hehehehe.
The output is produced so- So far, shapes,
and it knows, I mean, a lot lots of tic-tac-toe games and so,
and just, barrels on.
So there's probably lots of duplication with our library classes
here. This is a formatter.
Okay. So here's what I'm gonna do.
Move anything with
a display other than the list
of turns to milestone
three. Focus.
First two milestones.
On the, uhm,
you know, invisible board play.
See, has it written checklists yet?
Yeah. And do the checklists have good test files and,
Okay.
Basics CLI. Match system.
Invisible board play. Okay. And I'll take
How are we doing? Agent. Okay.
Okay. Test from game engine, did it push anything?
Yes, test. We're up to 152 passing tests.
Let's see if get up the grease. First of all,
do we have any branches? Yes,
we do. There it is. And
do we have any pull requests? No. So let's open a PR.
Great. So, that'll give us some feedback on the test,
and we will also get Jim and I starting a good review.
So, how do I feel about how we're doing?
Whoa, man, the time is flying. Um,
so I'm not feeling great about that. I
thought we were- gonna get to our first umm,
game much faster. And we're producing,
like, way more code than we needed to, right?
Like, if I hadn't taken this big design document approach to it,
but instead I had taken the approach of,
you know, more targeted directions,
shorter directions and so on, we would've gotten a shorter- We were files,
we would've gotten a result faster. That would've,
you know, de-risked the project a little more.
So, umm, nah,
not feeling great about, about, umm,
about that. But, uhh,
uhh, the hope
is that if we've got a solid mod- a little make doing the other
stuff a little easier. Okay,
so what? So,
yeah, what's up, Bill's that way. What are these,
Jacks? What are these feeling,
Jacks? These
code coverage tests.
What happened with our tests? Yes.
Hm.
How do we get code coverage, but I'm not.
This. Interesting.
Okay. We're still working on this.
Oh no, this is, this is happening on the background agent,
so I don't think I've got anything going on here,
so let's close that. I think we're good here.
Let's close that. Let's close that.
And so I think I'm okay to switch branches right now.
I guess I can open up the terminal.
Actually, I'll just do that here. here.
Okay, the last thing we were working on is ours.
Yeah, our CLI guy here.
Yes, and we got our visual display,
milestone three, that's very. very good.
But, I'm not sure if the checklist section in
four is matching the milestones.
Let's make a background agent deal with that problem so we can
go ahead and switch workspaces. Ours.
Switch branches and start checking on the other one.
Umm. So,
what do we want you to do? We want you to make
sure that the
checklist,
in section 4 are aligned,
the milestones in section 5.
Combine the sections.
Over for the animals. Umm,
section 5.
Now, we can safely,
,search branches. Okay.
Orange.
Okay. . . . .
Uhh, we got lots of type errors.
That's not nice. Not cool.
So, the agent has not been obedient.
It's not checking its work. Usually it is much better by doing it than
this. But we should just just .
. It's affected when we didn't see those pushes showing up.
But, it's surprising to me .
. . that we got .
. . that we got that far. Of course,
that could have shown up in a more recent commit.
Let's see how many commits we've got in the .
. . PR now. Yeah.
Yeah. It's .
. .
it's um . .
.
these ones have been relatively okay,
I think. So .
. . let's go back . .
. to chat here and say .
.
how he is working on type errors. Isn't it exciting?
The window in the right hand. And, slide
I'll see what it's in the middle because I'm going to interrupt it here.
It's about ready to run tests. Yes. So
this is a good time to interrupt.
Okay.
So, where are we?
We don't understand what- What?
What's going on with these ta- favorite tests? And that is of- as
of what commit? Do we have the same thing happening here?
Oh, oh, let's look at the actions.
Oh, it opened a new pull request. What's that all about?
I'm gonna check this for the most. Oh, well, that's the thing we just
did. It just did it on a branch. And
so we can actually,
We can just- we can just merge that sucker.
Okay, umm.
This is the umm, this is just our design talk.
And we just don't really want it on this branch. So,
we can just merge it. Um,
cursor just does that by default.
Okay. Let's make sure we don't have any new branches showing
up. What we're already expecting.
Umm. Okay. So.
We have eight commits on here at this
point.
And this one was green as far as the test go.
Oh.
I see how, I see how it is right now.
You
Yeah, still got a lot broken.
Bomber here is if I start
fixing these. I'm gonna have an emerge complex.
I am very eager to
get to done on this first section.
Alright, I'm going to start investigating anyway.
I want to know what these testifiers make.
Oh, these are type errors.
This is not. But I think what's happening here is that the-
It's stopping because the first build
in the matrix fails. I think that's what it's doing.
It's forcing an early quit.
Umm, okay.
So let's go ahead and create a design dock for the,
umm, for the react components.
And we'll see you in
Do we commit and push?
Oh, he's checking on it to make sure. So we should be seeing a
new build.
What is this one?
Oh, it's the main, it's just the main branch.
It's the merge on the main branch, right? . . .
Okay, great. We're done.
With as much as they're- gonna do there. Let's get a poll.
Let's see what we have to fix.
There's the fine but never used. used.
How are we doing? We got a bunch of new typers.
Cheers!
Okay. Umm,
so, I think our CLI dock should be in pretty good shape now.
Let's see if we get them out. Also in the structure that way we
want it.
This is not looking like what I'm expecting.
Oh, it's- Because I'm on the wrong branch that got merged to Maine.
Mm, mm,
mm, mm, mm, mm. So let's just go look at it.
And Maine. Let me see how we're doing.
Mm, mm. See we're on the Maine branch.
And we're- Where is it?
I'm pretty sure we merged it.
So, what happened? Where did
we merge it to? Thank you.
Don't me. Not good.
Not what we wanted.
Not what we wanted. That's too bad.
Oh, and we're modifying the wrong document. How did that happen?
I must be trying to move too fast. That,
Looks no good. Good.
Alright, we're green. So do we get a green build on
this branch? No,
cause we haven't pushed this yet.
Umm, hmmm.
Stay in this. Yes.
Oh, hopefully we're gonna get a green build.
Okay, so I'm looking at the time here, and I would say,
no. I'm not happy with how things are going here.
I was hoping I would be done with this at
hour one, and I'm almost done with hour two,
so. We're not gonna get nearly as far as I had hoped to with
this project, but there.
Welcome to software. Okay.
While I'm waiting for that, let's fix this.
Yes.
I'm just gonna be a lot more specific this time.
.
So, we should have a look.
Ah, shoot. She didn't do that.
Alright.
Okay. All
right, let's go check on our build. Yay!
Oh, green! Whoo! Okay,
finally! So,
let's look at the PR. That took way too long.
We took way too big a crank there,
you know what I mean? Like, you want fast,
tight cycles, not- like, an hour and a half to get to your first
commit. That's dunk. Umm.
Alright, let's work on review comments.
And that's the difference.
Mm good.
Good, good, good, good,
good, good, good. Let me,
let me see what else is here. Umm,
and I've served a amount of code for tic-tac-toe.
Absurd!
And it's not good to have so much code for tic-tac-toe.
Alright, let's umm.
What do we want to do next? We want to,
we want to fix the review.
You comments and get the darn thing merged.
So.
Let's see here. You
How are we now organized? Are C.L.A.
now organized?
I mean, are we really organized the right way?
The thing that I'm finding very frustrating about this exercise right now is I'm
just writing docs and that you're not seeing me in the code,
and this is not what my life is ordinarily like.
I mean, I use these docs,
but I- It's been a lot more time in the code, and I'm not
demonstrating that in this exercise,
and I'm not doing that because I'm trying to get stuff done fast,
and I'm not actually moving that very- very
fast. I mean, I'm creating lots of classes and tests,
but I'm not showing results at the speed I would like.
And I'm not, uhm,
I'm not showing coding skills
or kind of understanding of code,
and that's frustrating to me.
That doesn't feel good.
Okay, I think this checklist is ready. I'm gonna- a Or I'll run it
through one more test that I sometimes often do,
and I use generalized specially for this.
And, let's say,
actually, O3 is especially good at this.
I'm gonna ask. It's good. Okay.
Okay.
Alright, we got a design document for React,
for the React stuff.
And we probably have some review.
Agreeeee. Agreeeee.
Ooh, I don't like this. I don't
like incomplete before. What is incomplete here?
here. 8
Let's start fixing. SINGING. The first issues,
and then I want to dig deeper into this whole placeholder thing.
That makes me uncomfortable. Umm,
so. I'm gonna just tell
it to work on sections one through five.
Please address the review guide in the section.
I'm not sure. Those ones are fine. Bye.
What's the name of the branch again? And we'll see you
Oh, oh, oh, oh. I don't want to do that here. I want to
do that as a background date. Okay.
Okay, we got- Yeah. Right there. A lot of tabs open here.
Let's see where we are. We
don't need that anymore.
We are done with our design dock,
I think. Oh yeah, we're now just evaluating the
order.
Oh, hot, good, good, good. We got the analysis. If you adopt that sequence
and each milestone, each item superrequisites.
Yeah. O1 is super good at that particular problem of
making sure things are done in the right order. It doesn't always- get everyone
right, but it typically does pretty good.
So, You
I usually work on things that are way more complicated than tic-tac-toe.
Of course so, does everybody? Umm, so that's probably why,
Like, this, structure is working really well for me ordinarily,
but working poorly for me with tic-tac-toe,
I'm guessing. Okay.
Umm. Let's see,
what am I looking at here? Oh,
I'm going to do it, looking at review feedback. So
we're getting review- review. Review feedback in, so I need to spend some time
looking at React components. Uhh,
alright. Game board,
game cell, game status, game controls,
move history, game analysis,
player info, game sex. Ooh,
this is a lot of components. Reduced
to the most.
Just.
Well, in the time remaining, there's no way,
even if we copy a whole another repo that we
have. Are we gonna get- the
rest APIs, you know,
and I don't think. Umm,
let's take a look.
So my son and I started working on- we've been working
on little games all summer. And we
have one for- so here that,
uhh.
That's the best way of doing that. See ya.
Uhh, I'm happy here.
There we go.
What is going on? Mm.
Uhh, duh. You
Okay, now what I want you to do is- is.
Alright.
How are we doing on review feedback here?
I think it's just done, I think. Thank you.
Great. So we should have some new commits,
and we've got a build going on now. See
what we're doing here. Ahhh.
Great. All right.
Okay. Thank you. Then the other problem we had was that there was,
like, un-implemented methods or something like that.
So what was that all about? So let's see if we can figure that
out. And we gotta get that merged.
I mean, that thing, this was supposed to be our very first thing,
and it's dragging on and on. Umm.
It wasn't right here.
Okay, interesting. Okay,
so. Let's merge it.
Now it starts in duplicate stuff.
up.
Okay. So those just all have to do with the AI and how good
the AI is, but it won't break. So I'm gonna go ahead and merge
it.
And, Umm, we,
so we can build our CLI on top of it.
I don't think we've actually started the agent to implement the
CLI. We were,
I think, reorganizing the structure of the checklist.
Uhh, okay, we're ready.
We are ready. So let's
have a background agent. minute.
You know, the one thing I'm wondering about. out.
Oh, first of all, we gotta commit that. Umm,
and then I'm wondering if it actually got good instruction about
how to write the tests.
This is correct.
I'm not seeing the test classes.
I'm not seeing that they were done correctly.
And
they're just creating some, ehm,
seems kind of silly, okay. Okay.
I think we're ready. I think that's good. Please
implement. Umm.
Mm.
Alright. So,
we've hit 30 minutes. So So We should be polishing now,
but we still haven't seen a playable game.
So, from a kind of risk management standpoint,
I'm not happy with that at all.
Umm. We've got lots of code,
it's got lots of unit tests, but we've never even seen it run yet.
So, shouldn't have, shouldn't have happened that way.
Umm.
We're not gonna get to react or the Fastify app.
Even though we've kind of got some start on that.
The main thing is gonna be to get through to getting
this command stuff done.
Oh, oh, oh. I just realized we
gave it a checklist without committing it.
It's working on the wrong version of it. I am
glad we caught that.
Oh, yeah, we're in.
Okay.
Hmmm.
Alright,
first let me verify that this is actually the-
Thanks.
Yeah. For sure. here.
Silly. Okay.
Let's tuck that up. Okay.
Let's make sure I'm on the right branch.
Interesting.
I just pushed that tool.
Alright. Put that on the wrong branch.
Thank you very
Let's make sure this is the change I thought it was.
And that's it.
Yeah. Okay. So we need a cherry pick.
Okay.
Actually, I need to just murder it this way.
One further complete test in code. For the phase.
Okay, well I can't really mess with this, I'm not a time.
Let's see how we're doing. and
on our command lane.
We got 15 minutes. Yes.
Uhh, okay. So.
I think. Let's see what branch am
I in.
Actually, this is not the right way to go. .
What is the name of the repository? All right.
So, what's he doing?
Alright. Let's try.
Mmm, heh, heh. Mm-hmm.
Umm, hm, hm,
hm, hm. You
Okay. Okay.
Okay, we're kind of on the final stretch.
We- we demonstrated that we had playable AI,
so. Like, uh, tic-tac-toe.
We, like, met the objective. Umm,
but we did it and, kind of.
At the last minute. And umm,
I'm very uncomfortable with that.
Umm, so let's do a little retrospective.
What went wrong? Well, I think fundamentally what went wrong is that I'm using,
you know, these big design documents that I use for,
kind of, really complex projects that- are,
kind of, two or three-day efforts.
Umm, and usually what happens is that the AI can,
you know, generate, you know, a milestone at a time,
test it and so on. There's review cycles in between.
I get involved, you know, oftentimes in- and so- and I- I
review those docs a lot more, umm,
carefully to actually- Actually, make sure I'm kind of happy with the design.
And I try to compress that,
you know, into this three-hour chunks.
So, the design documents were too long for the
kind of quick turns we needed to make in order to do
six iterations or, you know, four or five iterations in
three hours. And, um, so if I had to do it over again,
the way that I would do it is by using a much shorter kind
of design approach, um,
with, with smaller inputs, and that way we would get tighter cycles.
And, uh, we might, um,
we would then get, you know, additional iterations worth of work.
Um, you know,
what went well, well, I did- kids.
See that the agent that was working on the CLI was never gonna finish
in time. Uh, I mean,
it's now- it's just now working on implementing that,
you know, Section 421.
It'll be a while before it gets through all of those sections to get,
you know, three different milestones of the command line tool.
Um, and I pivoted to- who,
you know, just using Oakliffe's generator and a quick prompt to
knock out something really fast so that,
you know, I wouldn't be caught with nothing at the end of the-
of the cycle. So, um,
thanks very much for, um,
giving me an opportunity to, uh, to interview with this.
I look forward to our conversation. And,
um, I'll get this kind of cleaned up and pushed,
but, um, I won't. Uh,
anything else that gets pushed, uh,
I'll definitely make sure it gets marked with late or something like that.
And so it's, like, really clear kind of where we end it.
Thanks again.
And where is our,
err,
um. You